Drink the Dragon Bone soup.
就把這龍骨喝了吧
Drink it immediately.
你快點喝
Otherwise, it will become stinkier when it's cold.
再不喝涼了就更臭了都得
Qianqian stole Dragon Bone for Han Shuo.
芊芊為了韓爍盜取龍骨
It seems she really loves him.
可見真心
But till now
可到現在
they haven't slept together.
他二人還沒有圓房
Could Qianqian be blamed?
這問題能出現在芊芊身上嗎
Han Shuo is an ambitious man.
韓爍此人狼子野心
I was so careless.
這事是我大意了
I think he just want to use Qianqian
我看 他就是想利用芊芊
to steal the Dragon Bone.
謀取龍骨
But...
可
But just now Young Master Han
可剛剛韓少君
fed the first spoon of Dragon Bone soup
可是將第一口龍骨湯
to Her Highness.
親口餵給三公主的
He just pretended to be nice.
做做樣子誰不會啊
At last, the Dragon Bone soup
可最後這龍骨
was drunk up by him.
還不是讓他喝了
He is the first person
敢在我眼皮底下玩弄心術的
who dared to play tricks under my eyes.
他還是頭一個
I will turn Han Shuo
我要將韓爍
into an ordinary person again.
重新變成一個廢人
Then, how about Her Highness?
那 三公主她
If I must raise a dog,
就算養條狗
I will raise an obedient dog.
也要養條聽話的留在身邊
Good morning, Young Master Han.
見過韓少君
I heard that you had drunk Dragon Bone soup.
屬下聽聞少君已經服下龍骨
I just sent this good news to Xuanhu City.
剛剛將喜訊傳回了玄虎城
I never thought that people from Xuanhu City could know it.
想不到玄虎城的勢力竟滲透至此
It is my pleasure to meet you.
幸會了
Minister Yang.
楊司戶
I must say that you're very thoughtful.
少君深謀遠慮
Thanks to a firework show at the Third Princess's Mansion last night,
多虧昨夜三公主府上的一場煙花
I found that the Second Princess was tracing me.
二郡主追查我時形跡敗露
So I could find this chance to meet you.
我才有機會與您相見
The firework show last night
昨夜那場煙花
was not my idea.
並非我所為
I am not that smart.
我算不到這麼精準
You're so humble.
少君過謙了
Now, you have got rid of your heart disease.
如今少君心疾已除
We are halfway to success.
我們計劃已成一半
Next, when a chance arises,
接下來只要伺機而動
our well-equipped troops will move southward
精兵南下
and conquer Huayuan City.
一舉拿下花垣城
The black stone mine of Huayuan City
花垣城的烏石礦
will become Hu's.
就要改姓虎了
Minister Yang is a woman.
楊司戶身為女子
Wouldn't you be happier if you stay in Huayuan City?
在花垣城豈不是更如魚得水
Why do you want to work for me?
為何會效忠於我呢
Though I am in Huayuan City,
我雖身在花垣城
I concern about families of Xuanhu City.
但心繫玄虎城的家人
I wish to do everything for you.
屬下願為少君效犬馬之勞
If that is so,
既然如此
could you do me a favor?
韓某有一事相求
Please tell me.
少君請說
In future, if anyone argues about the Third Princess,
日後若有人論及三公主之事
please defend her
還望楊司戶出言維護
and protect her.
護她周全
I don't want Qianqian to fall into any trouble again.
我不希望芊芊再發生任何意外了
Yes.
是
Your Highness.
二郡主
We had better report to Her Majesty.
我們還是稟告城主吧
Our mission failed last night.
昨夜任務失敗
If my mother knows it,
讓母親知道了
she will think that I am useless.
肯定又會嫌我無用
But your wound is severe.
可您的傷勢太重了
Perhaps if Her Majesty sees your wound,
或許城主看見您的傷
she will not blame you.
就不會責怪您了
My mother took care of Qianqian at Yueli Mansion all night yesterday.
昨天母親在月璃府照顧芊芊一夜
Please don't bother her.
就別再讓她勞神了
I heard the Third Princess went to Ancestral Hall and grabbed the Dragon Bone away.
聽說三公主直奔宗祠搶了龍骨
She cured the heart disease of Young Master Han.
替韓少君治癒了心疾
In the past, only Her Majesty and the Crown Princess
歷來都是隻有城主和少城主
know the whereabouts of the Dragon Bone.
知曉龍骨的下落
How did the Third Princess know that
您說三公主為什麼知道
the Dragon Bone was hidden at Ancestral Hall?
龍骨藏在了祖宗祠堂
Has Her Majesty decided to pass the throne to...
是不是城主已經決定傳位給
Zi Zhu.
梓竹
Don't be suspicious without reason.
不準胡亂猜忌
There must be something we don't know.
這其中肯定有誤會
I guess that Qianqian
我猜三妹
found the Dragon Bone by chance.
不過是湊巧找到龍骨
She fired fireworks at the mansion last night.
那她昨夜在府上放煙花
Is that a coincidence too?
也是湊巧嗎
She also made you severely injured.
還害您受這麼重的傷
What are you watching?
看什麼呢
This is a serial drama.
這 這是連續劇
Don't think that stealing a Dragon Bone is all I want to do.
你以為我偷個龍骨就完了
I still want to do other things.
這還有後續呢
What are those things?
哪裡來的後續
Is everything ready?
都準備好了嗎
Young Master, please rest assured.
少君 放心吧
I don't know if she likes to eat it.
不知道她喜不喜歡吃
It is expensive.
貴著
Where did my Kung Fu go?
我的武功呢
I am a worthless person.
我是個廢人
What should I do?
我該怎麼辦
I never heard that Soul Missing Powder has such a side effect.
沒聽說斷魂散有這個副作用啊
Qianqian.
芊芊
Qianqian, what is wrong with you?
芊芊 你怎麼了
After I was poisoned,
中毒以後
I found myself losing the ability of fighting.
我竟然武功全無
I will be
我陳芊芊
a worthless person forever.
從此以後就是個廢人了
My mother will set up a Kung Fu contest for me.
母親特意為我開設的武試擢選
But I can't attend it anymore.
我也不能參加了
Come on.
來
How do you feel now?
你現在什麼感覺
Hope
絕
-less.
望
How strange! I want to eat pomegranates.
突然好想吃石榴
There should be no pomegranates in this season.
這個季節應該沒有石榴
That's right.
也對
A person without Kung Fu
武功盡失的人
doesn't deserve to eat pomegranates.
不配吃石榴
Bai Ji, go to buy pomegranates.
白芨 去買石榴
Yes, sir.
是
Young Master, pomegranates.
少君 石榴
Pomegranates.
石榴
I just want to see if they are available.
我只是想看看有沒有
Now I am relieved.
有就放心了
I don't have appetite.
沒有胃口
I can't eat now.
吃不下
Take away.
拿走
Han Shuo.
少君
Why don't I write a letter
不如我修書一封
to dissolve our marriage contract?
你我解除婚約吧
You can seek refuge with Chen Chuchu.
去投靠我二姐陳楚楚吧
No. You...
不 你
I am a commoner already.
我已經是廢人一個了
Everyone supports Chuchu. She will have a bright future.
二姐受眾人擁戴 前途似錦
She can protect you.
定會護你周全
The Second Princess is severely injured.
二郡主身負重傷
She is not well.
情況並不怎麼好啊
What's wrong with her?
什麼情況
Who dared to
哪個混賬
injure her? Bastard!
竟敢加害於她
The Second Princess was conducting a secret mission that night.
那晚二郡主執行祕密任務
It was agreed that fireworks should be the signal for action.
約好了以煙花為號
But someone fired fireworks in advance.
不知道是誰
We don't know who that person is.
提前把煙花給點了
The secret mission of the Second Princess was unveiled.
二郡主的行動就暴露了
So she fought with enemies.
這不跟人家火拼上了嗎
Why did fireworks hurt Chuchu?
煙花怎麼會炸到楚楚呢
The lighting of fireworks
煙花
perhaps was an accident.
興許只是個意外
Young Master Han should consider
韓少君還是可以考慮一下
Chuchu...
在二姐
I will not leave you.
我是不會離開你的
Your Highness should take a rest.
三公主好生休息
If there is anything you want,
有什麼事
please ask me.
儘管吩咐韓某
Go.
走
I will teach you a lesson.
你給我等著
They have gone.
他們已經走了
He refused to leave.
居然不肯走
Fine.
罷了
I will find another chance
日後再尋機會
to send him to Chuchu in the future.
將他送到楚楚身邊吧
He will not stay with a good-for-nothing forever.
他也不會一直留在一個廢物身邊
To save my life,
能保住小命
I have already used up my strength and acting skills.
已經耗盡我全身力氣和演技了
Pomegranates.
石榴
Your Highness.
三公主
Lord Sangqi is dispatching an order of Her Majesty.
桑奇大人來傳城主令了
Dispatching an order?
傳令
What is the order?
傳什麼令
By the order of Her Majesty...
城主令
Take care.
慢點
The Crown Prince of Xuanhu City Han Shuo
玄虎城少城主韓爍
coaxed the Third Princess Chen Qianqian to steal the Dragon Bone.
魅惑三公主陳芊芊盜取龍骨
It is decreed that a bone should be taken from Han Shuo,
今著令取其骨一根
so as to ensure a correct understanding of the matter and give peace to the people.
以正視聽 以安民心
Take what?
取什麼 取
Don't move.
別動
Han Shuo.
韓爍
Han Shuo. Let me go.
韓爍 放開
Let me go. Han Shuo.
放開 韓爍
Sangqi.
桑奇
Your Highness.
三公主
After you stole the Dragon Bone,
你盜取龍骨
civilians and officials in the city
這城中的百姓和文武百官啊
all wanted the justice to be served.
不肯罷休
That's why Her Majesty came up this idea.
城主才出此計策
She only wants to protect you.
那是為了保你周全
I...
我
The City Owner is coming.
城主駕到
That can't be true.
不是吧
I brought a big trouble to Han Shuo.
我該不是把韓爍給坑了吧
Let me go.
放開
Mother.
母親
Mother. Why are you doing this?
母親 你這是什麼意思
Because Han Shuo drank up Dragon Bone soup,
韓爍喝了龍骨
he damaged the fortune of Huayuan City.
壞了我花垣城的運勢
I am the City Owner of Huayuan City.
我身為花垣城城主
I will take a bone from his body
要取他的一根骨頭
to assuage the people's anger.
以平民憤
Take a bone?
取骨頭
How big should be the bone?
取多大的骨頭
Is this big enough?
這麼大可不可以
Silly girl.
傻孩子
That is depend on the size of the Dragon Bone.
龍骨多大 就取多大
Guards.
來人
Yes, Your Majesty.
在
Take a rib from Han Shuo's body.
將韓爍的一根肋骨取下
Don't do that.
不要 不要不要
Don't do that. Han Shuo.
不要 韓爍
Let me go.
放開
Han Shuo.
韓爍
Don't approach him.
不要過去
Mother.
母親
Han Shuo.
韓爍
Mother. I beg you. Mother.
母親 求您了 母親
Let me go.
他 放開
Han Shuo.
韓爍
Go away.
走開
Go away. Go away.
走開 走開 走開
Mother. Mother.
母親 母親
I stole the Dragon Bone alone.
龍骨是我一個人偷的
It has nothing to do with Han Shuo.
跟韓爍沒有關係
If you take a rib from his body,
你 你要取走他一根肋骨
he will be either disabled or died.
他不死也是廢了
Mother. Han Shuo is a proud man.
母親 韓爍他心高氣傲的
You had better kill him than disable him.
你要廢了他還不如殺了他
Killing him is better.
殺了他更好
Without his coaxing,
沒有他的蠱惑
you would not make such a big trouble.
你敢惹出這麼大的亂子嗎
Do you know what people say nowadays?
你知不知道現在外邊的傳聞
You have become a bane of civilians.
你都成了百姓口中的災星了
Don't move.
不要動
Mother.
母親
I will bear all the consequences.
我陳芊芊一人做事一人當
I forced Han Shuo to drink Dragon Bone soup.
龍骨是我逼韓爍喝的
If you want to take a bone, take my bone.
你們要取骨取我的
I am his rib.
我就是他的肋骨
Don't move.
不要動
Drag Chen Qianqian away.
把陳芊芊給我拉開
Please don't. Please don't.
不要 不要 不要
Han Shuo. Han Shuo.
韓爍 韓爍
Your Highness.
三公主
Han Shuo. Wake up.
韓爍 你醒醒
Han Shuo. Han Shuo. Wake up.
韓爍 韓爍醒醒
If you don't wake up, I can't protect you. Han Shuo.
你再不醒我護不住你了 韓爍
Separate them.
拉開
Please don't. Please don't.
不要 不要 不要
Mother.
母親
You don't know
你不知道韓爍
how important Han Shuo is to me?
他對我有多重要的
Let me go.
放開
Pull her away. Pull her away.
拉開 拉開
Han Shuo. Wake up.
韓爍 你醒醒
All right.
好
You can take my bone.
要取骨你們取我的
I know you don't dare to do that.
我知道你們不敢
Mother.
母親
You can punish me if you wish.
你罰我吧 要不然
Drag Chen Qianqian away.
把陳芊芊給我拉
I know you will not hurt me.
我知道你捨不得
Aren't you ashamed of yourself?
難道你不要臉面嗎
I am not.
不要
I am ashamed of you.
我要
Drag her away.
拉開
Please don't.
別 別
Han Shuo.
韓爍
Qianqian.
芊芊
Han Shuo. You have woken up.
韓爍 你醒了
I will not release my hands.
我不放手
If I release my hands, they will hurt you.
我放手他們要欺負你的
Han Shuo.
韓爍
Han Shuo. Sorry.
韓爍 對不起
I don't know things will turn out to be like this.
我不知道偷龍骨會這樣的
I just wanted to cure your heart disease.
我只是想治好你的心疾
But I never thought that you would be punished for my mistake.
但我沒有想你替我受罰的
You are pressing my wound.
你壓到我傷口了
Besides,
再說
if you keep hugging me like this,
你這樣抱著我
I will not be able to use my Kung Fu.
我也不好施展啊
Do you want to know
你想不想知道
how powerful I am after
被你治好的我
I was cured by you?
是什麼樣子的
Han Shuo. Han Shuo.
韓爍 韓爍
Don't hurt him.
別碰他
Who dares to hurt her?
誰敢動她
Nobody wants to hurt her.
沒人想動她
We just want to hurt you.
我們是想動你
Let Her Highness go.
你放開三公主
Please don't cry.
你別哭啊
I am alright.
我這不好好的嗎
Sorry.
對不起
It is my fault.
都怪我
If you keep crying,
你再哭下去
I will get a heart disease again.
我心疾都要犯了
How can it be possible?
怎麼可能
The Dragon Bone I stole is real.
我偷的龍骨是真的
Is it true if you take a bone from my body,
是不是從我身上取了骨
you will never blame Qianqian
就沒人再追究
for stealing the Dragon Bone?
芊芊偷龍骨的責任了
Please do it.
動手吧
You are crazy.
你瘋了
You will lose so much blood and your wound will get infected.
失血過多 傷口感染
Eventually you will die.
你會沒命的呀
Please don't blame Qianqian anymore.
以後別再怪罪芊芊了
Do you really want to risk your life
你為了芊芊
for Qianqian?
真的連命都不要
Let's calm down.
我 我們都再冷靜一下
I think that there should be other options.
我覺得 還有其他方法
You don't understand how important the Dragon Bone means to civilians.
你不明白龍骨對於百姓的意義
You stole the Dragon Bone
你偷盜龍骨
to cure my heart disease.
為我治癒心疾
I must be punished.
我必須受罰
Then you can be exonerated.
才能替你解圍
Qianqian.
芊芊
You are a princess of the city.
你作為一城郡主
People call you the Third Princess.
又讓人喊你三公主
You have to shoulder
有些責任
your responsibility.
你是逃不掉的
Princess.
郡主
Is that mean if I was not a princess,
是不是不當郡主
I would not shoulder any responsibility?
就可以不負責任了
Do you know what you are talking about?
你知道你在說什麼嗎
Mother.
母親
I am not good at either literature or Kung Fu.
我本來就文不成武不就的
I am a good-for-nothing.
根本就沒有什麼用
Please abolish my title and let me be a commoner.
你廢我為庶人吧
I will not be
三公主
the Third Princess anymore.
我不當了
Nonsense.
胡說
You are my daughter.
你是我的女兒
How can you refuse to be a princess?
怎麼能不當郡主呢
Your Majesty. It looks that Her Highness
城主 看這三公主
loves Young Master Han very much.
和韓少君情比金堅
If we don't make a compromise,
若再這樣僵持下去
I am afraid that it will be harder for Her Highness
恐怕三公主的境遇
to handle the situation.
會更加難了
Qianqian.
芊芊
Do you know what will become of you
你知道你成了庶人之後
if you are a commoner?
會是什麼境遇嗎
Han Shuo will stay with me.
我有韓爍
I am not afraid.
我不怕
Do you really trust me?
你這麼信任我
By the order of Her Majesty, (City Owner's Mansion)
城主詔令
Chen Qianqian, the daughter of City Owner, is stubborn and disobedient.
城主之女陳芊芊頑劣不堪
Disregarding ancestral traditions,
罔顧祖宗傳統
she stole the Dragon Bone and damaged the fortune of the city.
擅動龍骨 壞我城運
Therefore, it is decreed that she should become a ccommoner
廢為庶人
and be deprived of any special rights.
免去一切特權
She should go back to the mansion to reflect on her mistakes.
回府反省
Without being summoned by Her Majesty,
沒有城主召見
she should not leave the mansion.
不得擅自出府
Isn't the Third Princess the most favorite daughter of Her Majesty?
這城主不是最寵愛三公主嗎
Why was she deprived of the title?
怎麼說廢為庶人就廢了
I am so surprised.
上來直接就廢了
Now how should we read
那咱們準備懲罰三公主的公文
the announcement about punishing the Third Princess?
該怎麼念呢
Her Majesty has gained the upper hand by taking the initiative.
城主這是先下手為強呀
Since the Third Princess has become a commoner,
既然三公主已經廢為庶人
shall we wind up
那盜取龍骨的事
the case of stealing the Dragon Bone?
就到此為止吧
I agree.
下官附議 下官附議
Then the Crown Princess will be...
那少城主之位豈不是
OK. Dismiss.
也好 都散了吧
Minister Pei.
裴司學
I heard that
小人剛才聽說
because the Third Princess stole the Dragon Bone,
三公主盜取龍骨
she had been deprived of the title and become a commoner.
已經被廢為庶人了
What did you say?
你說什麼
There are rumors that
這坊間都在傳聞
the disease of Young Master has been cured,
少君的病好了
but the Third Princess has been deprived of the title.
三公主卻被廢了
It is true.
可不是嗎
People all say that
現在都說
the heart disease of Young Master Han has been cured.
韓少君心疾痊癒
He can defeat ten persons at one time.
一個能打十個
How could that be?
怎麼可能
Young Master Han will die before his 20th birthday.
韓少君明明活不過二十歲
If he does not die,
他不死
how could our master
咱們公子
marry the Third Princess?
和三公主的婚約怎麼辦
She is not the Third Princess anymore.
都已經不是三公主了
I don't know how Lin Qi
這還不知道林七
will treat the Third Princess.
會如何為難三公主啊
Spendthrift Chen Qianqian was deprived of the title.
敗家子陳芊芊被貶為庶人
She has fallen from grace.
徹底失寵了
She stole the Dragon Bone and damaged the fortune of the city.
擅動龍骨 壞我城運
Only she could do such kind of things.
還真稱得上她三公主的稱號
If Huayuan City is governed by such a kind of person,
我花垣城要是落到這種人手裡
our lives will be doomed.
還能好嗎
Now, she not only has been deprived of the title,
就是 她現在身份都沒了
but also has lost the ability of fighting.
還武功全失
Doesn't that mean she is just a worthless person?
那不徹徹底底就是個廢人了嗎
The creditors will go to her house and ask her to pay pack money.
那些債主還不討上門去呀
Do you think that
你們說
the Third Princess will still
三公主她以後
come to the clan school?
還來宗學堂嗎
Only princesses and female relatives of officials
宗學堂
can go to the clan school.
只有郡主和官員女子才能讀
She is no longer a princess.
她都被廢了
Of course she can't come here.
當然不能來
Do you think she did it on purpose?
你們說 她是不是故意的
Then the Third Princess doesn't need to go to school anymore.
這樣三公主再也不用來上學了
She just want to evade school.
為了逃課
We should stop calling her the Third Princess.
已經不能再叫三公主了
Let's go.
走吧
Your Highness.
郡主
Why don't you worry about the Third Princess?
您怎麼一點都不替三公主擔心啊
She dares to steal the Dragon Bone.
她連龍骨都敢動
There's no need for me to worry about her.
哪還需要我替她擔心
My feet have been disabled by poison for many years.
我雙腿中毒廢了這麼多年
She never said that she would steal the Dragon Bone
她也沒有說要盜取龍骨
to treat me.
為我療傷
But the Dragon Bone can't cure your disease.
可 龍骨也不治您這個呀
But what if it can cure me?
可它萬一能治呢
Your Highness.
郡主
Forget it.
罷了
Actually, I think that
我倒覺得
she is better than before.
她現在像個樣子了
In order to save another person's life,
能為了救別人
she is willing to give up her title.
自己被廢為庶人
Anyway, my mother loves her.
反正母親也寵愛她
Whether she is a princess or not
當不當郡主於她而言
makes no difference to her.
沒什麼兩樣
Zi Nian.
梓年
Bring the shawl for me.
你去幫我把披肩拿來
Yes.
是
Is this the book that Your Highness
大郡主要找的
is looking for?
可是這一本
Your Highness.
大郡主
If you need anything,
您有什麼需要
just ask me.
吩咐小的就行
Please don't ask Su Mu for help.
不要找蘇沐
Why can't I ask him for help?
為什麼不要找他
He is not qualified to serve Your Highness.
他不配伺候郡主
Why?
為什麼
He is a musician.
他就是個樂人
I don't know why
也不知道為什麼
he is at the clan school?
把他安排在宗學堂
I think
在我看來
musicians are not different from
樂人與我們常人
ordinary people.
並沒有什麼不同
Please don't talk about others behind their backs.
不要在背後妄議別人
Your Highness, you always only mind your own business.
大郡主向來不愛多管閒事
Why did you speak for Su Mu today?
為何今日要替蘇沐出頭
He is the only one
他是這麼多年來
who has squatted down to talk to me in all these years.
唯一一個蹲下來跟我說話的人
It is my negligence.
是小的疏忽了
That's all right.
無妨
I just think
我只是覺得
he treats me differently.
他於旁人 待我有些不同
You can't enter Yueli Mansion without permission.
你們不準擅闖月璃府
Chen Qianqian is just a commoner.
她現在只是庶人陳芊芊
She is nobody.
什麼都不是
I am afraid of nothing.
我有什麼不敢的
Get out of the way.
給我讓開
Pay back money. Pay the debt.
還錢 還債
You can't go in.
你們不能進去
Lin Qi.
林七
What are you doing here?
你這是幹什麼呀
Of course for revenge and protecting our rights.
當然是有仇報仇 有冤申冤嘍
Now, everyone can speak.
來 說
I have a complaint.
小的有冤要申
The Third Princess lives in luxury.
三公主府生活奢華
Yueli Mansion ordered some glazed utensils from my shop.
從小店訂購了一批琉璃盞用具
Five hundred pieces in total.
整整五百件
They only paid a half tael of silver for the deposit.
只付了紋銀五錢做定金
It's been two years.
可過去整整兩年了
The remaining 3,000 taels of silver have not been paid.
剩下三千兩尾款至今未付
I have been reminding them to make payment.
小的幾番催促
But they just said that they would pay tomorrow.
可 今日推明日
On the next day, they said the same thing.
明日推後日
As days went by,
明日復明日
my shop fell into debt.
致使小店日漸虧空啊
Is that true?
這這麼過分呢
Zi Rui. You...
梓銳 你去
I have a grocery store.
還有小人的雜貨店
Zi Rui placed orders to us. He is the Third Princess's favorite servant.
是三公主親信梓銳下單
Under the name of Princess's Mansion,
以公主府的名義
he asked my shop
要求小店
to produce a bamboo tube at a price far lower than the market price.
以遠低於市場價格定製一根竹筒
He also asked us to send 499 bamboo tubes
還要免費贈送三公主
to the Third Princess free of charge.
四百九十九根哪
The Third Princess drove us too hard.
三公主真是欺人太甚了
It is your honor to
你能為三公主效勞
serve the Third Princess.
是你們的榮幸
But today,
那今日呢
shouldn't she pay the debts?
她是不是該還債了
You...
你
The Third Princess should pay our debts.
三公主還我們的債
Pay our debts.
還我們的債
We have brought account books.
我們有賬本
Chen Qianqian.
陳芊芊
Pay back money.
還錢吧
Take them to settle the accounts.
帶她們去平賬
Pay back all the money we owed them.
把欠她們的錢全部還給她們
We must pay all debts even if it means emptying Yueli Mansion.
搬空月璃府也要還得清清楚楚
But...
不是
Go.
去
Move everything out.
搬東西去
OK. Go.
好 走
Go.
走走走
What are you doing?
你們幹什麼呀
You can't enter the house.
這不能進去 不能進去
No trespass.
你們不可以擅闖
I want this.
我要這個
-You can't enter. -You can't enter.
不能進去 不能進
What are you doing?
幹什麼呀你
Put things down.
把東西放下
Don't take them away.
不能拿東西
Don't take them. Put things down.
不能拿 放下
I want this.
這個 我要這個
Miss Lin is very impressive today
林七小姐今日威風
just like I was before.
與我往常無異
Be careful, because every dog has his day.
小心 風水輪流轉哪
Your Highness.
三公主
They are moving everything away.
他們把所有東西都搬走了
It doesn't matter.
沒事
I don't need them.
不要了
They are taking away antiques.
還有古董啊
No. I don't need them.
不 不要了
They are taking away jade articles and jewelry.
玉器和首飾也都搬走了
It doesn't matter.
給他
Your Highness.
三公主
Would you please stand up?
麻煩您起開一下
It looks that the chair you are sitting on is nice.
我看您身後這椅子挺不錯的
It is at least worth a few taels of silver.
怎麼著 也能抵幾兩銀子吧
Zi Rui.
梓銳
Calm down.
淡定
Go.
上
Lin Qi.
林七
Money and articles
錢 東西
all have been taken away. Are you satisfied?
都拿走了 夠了吧
That is only a warm-up.
這才哪兒到哪兒啊
The show is about to begin.
重頭戲還在後面呢
Someone. Bring the victim.
來人 帶苦主
You see. You see.
你看看 你看看 你看
On the day when Your Highness kidnapped the bridegroom,
公主搶親當日
you rode a horse on the street.
當街縱馬
My leg was broken by the horse.
造成小人腿 腿部骨折
I am now a disabled man.
落下殘疾呀
It has been long since that thing happened.
這麼久的事情了
Why didn't you come here until today?
你今天才來找我
Proof. Please show me the proof.
證據 你給我看證據
Everyone knows that
眾人都知道
you don't observe laws.
三公主你目無法度
You galloped on the street carelessly.
肆意縱馬 橫衝直撞
It is not strange that someone was knocked down by you.
那自然有老百姓被你撞到啊
Don't you think so?
您說是吧
You want to cheat me.
你訛我
The leg...
這腿他
I know that
我也知道
I lost position and would be subjected to humiliation.
我現在是虎落平陽被犬欺
I have nothing now
我什麼都沒有了
except my life.
我只有一條命了
If you want to do anything with me, just do it.
你們想怎麼樣就怎麼樣吧
Anyway, I am a worthless person.
反正我現在也是個廢人
I cannot resist you.
想反抗也反抗不了
In that case,
既然如此
please beat me.
你們打我吧
Han Shuo.
少君
I will deal with it.
我來解決
Even if they move everything out of Yueli Mansion,
他們就算把月璃府搬空了
I will support you.
我養你
That is real love.
真是情比金堅呀
I am here. Who dares to touch her?
有我在 誰敢
In the past, I was a little bit afraid of you
往日仗著你的身份
because of your position.
我讓你三分
But now, you are nothing but a civilian.
如今 你不過就是一介平民
You are only the Crown Prince of Xuanhu City.
我倒是要看看
I want to see
就憑著一個玄虎城的少君
how capable you can be.
你還能怎麼狂
Who dares to touch her?
我看誰敢動她
Pei Heng.
裴恆
Aren't they ministry footmen of the late Minister of Defense Pei?
這不是已故裴司軍的府兵嗎
Yes. Minister Pei came too.
是啊 還有裴司學呢
Yes. Why did he bring soldiers here?
對呀 他怎麼帶著人來了
Whether Qianqian is still the Third Princess or not,
不管芊芊是否還是三公主
she is still my fiancée.
她都是我裴恆
We have been engaged for more than ten years.
定親十幾年的未婚妻
I will pay back
她欠你們的東西
what she owed you.
我來歸還
Whether she owed you money or people,
錢財 人丁
you can go to Pei's Mansion and settle the accounts.
都可以到裴府去平賬
Speaking about the leg,
至於腿
you can take it from my body.
不如從我身上取
She is now a commoner.
她已經被廢為庶人了
She is not good enough for you.
她配不上你了
Besides,
再說了
Han Shuo had drunk Dragon Bone soup. He is robust.
韓爍喝了龍骨湯身強體健
Even if you wait for another two decades,
你就算再等個二十年
you will get nothing.
你都等不到
Whether Young Master Han had drunk Dragon Bone soup or not,
韓少君是否喝了龍骨
the teacher and student relationship between
都不會影響我對芊芊的
Qianqian and I will never change.
師生情誼
Minister Pei.
裴司學
Qianqian's mother
芊芊的生母
is the City Owner.
是當今城主
Qianqian's sister
芊芊的姐妹
is the future City Owner.
乃下一任城主
Even though Qianqian is a commoner,
芊芊即便是一介廢人
she is accompanied by the young master of Xuanhu City.
也有玄虎城少君相伴在側
She is still engaged to me.
也還與我有婚約在身
Qianqian
芊芊
is still the most honorable woman in Huayuan City.
仍然是花垣城最尊貴的女人
I know that you always protect her.
我就知道 你總是護著她
-Qianqian. -Qianqian.
芊芊 芊芊
I didn't use much force.
我沒使勁啊
You are deceiving me.
你 你訛我
Thanks.
謝謝
Let me accompany you.
我陪著你
Take a rest early.
早點休息吧
It feels good to be taken care of
原來生病有人照顧
in sickness.
是這個感覺
I will leave after you fall into sleep.
等你睡了我再走
I can't sleep.
我睡不著
Do you remember when we were kids,
你還記不記得
if you couldn't sleep,
小時候你睡不著
you would ask me to play the Qin for you.
拉著我彈琴給你聽
If I didn't want to play,
我不彈
you would punish me.
你便要罰我
Pei Heng. You are so good to me.
裴恆 你可真好
Are you leaving?
你要走了
It is getting late.
天色已晚
After all, we are not married.
畢竟男女有別
OK. I shall let you go.
好 不為難你了
I will come back tomorrow morning.
我明早再來
The man of Huayuan City
花垣男子
can't be trusted.
說一套做一套
He said he would not play the Qin.
嘴上說不彈琴
Actually, he practices the Qin secretly to seduce women.
實際上偷偷苦練 勾引女子
He is shameless.
真不要臉
It is time to take medicine.
喝藥
Why are you drinking so fast?
你喝那麼急幹嘛
Isn't it because you pour too much medicine into my mouth?
這不是你灌的嗎
I can't play the Qin.
我又不會彈琴
I can only feed you with medicine,
只能餵你藥
so that you can get well soon.
讓你早點好
I don't need you to play Qin for me.
我又不用你彈琴
I am very grateful to you
你能這麼來照顧我
for taking care of me.
我已經很感謝了
In the past, I was alone when I got sick.
以前生病都是一個人的
I am here with you this time.
這次有我在呢
Drink it.
來
In the past, when I got sick,
以前生病的時候
I also had to write script.
還要寫劇本
They would urge me to finish the script if I hadn't finished it.
劇本沒寫完還要被催
The film production crew was waiting for my script.
整個劇組的人都等著你
What is film production?
什麼劇組啊
I didn't dare to get sick.
不敢生病
I didn't have time for dating.
也沒時間談戀愛
I couldn't write a good love drama.
寫不好愛情劇還
I was mocked by actors.
還要被演員嘲笑
Drink slowly.
慢點啊
What nonsense are you talking about?
說什麼胡話呢
You are the daughter of Her Majesty.
你是城主之女
Who dares to force you?
誰敢逼你
You.
你呀
Big tiger.
大老虎
I...
我
Her Highness has got sick.
三公主病了
She needs a good rest.
需要好生休息
Tomorrow morning,
明天早上
you should lock up the door.
你把門鎖起來
No one is allowed to enter the house,
誰都不許進
especially Pei Heng.
尤其是裴恆
Understood.
明白
Chen Qianqian
陳芊芊
is really a long-lasting curse.
真是禍害遺千年
No one can beat her.
怎麼都搞不倒她
The business nowadays is not good.
如今的生意太不好做了
We lost a lot of money.
好多買賣都賠進去了
Lady. You had better think more about
小姐 你還是多用些心思
family businesses.
經營家業吧
We only lost money on small businesses.
賠錢的都是些小買賣
I can live on the mines of Lin family
我林家的礦山
for several lifetimes.
夠我吃上好幾輩子了
What do you worry about?
何必憂心呀
Though they are small businesses,
雖然只是小買賣
we can't let them lose more money.
可也不能任由它賠下去呀
Apart from other businesses,
不說別的營生
in our family,
咱們家
the most profitable businesses include mines
除了礦山之外
and the Music and Dance Academy.
最賺錢的教坊司
But musicians were taken away by the Third Princess.
樂人也都被三公主要走了
Speaking about the Music and Dance Academy, I am very angry.
說起這教坊司我就生氣
Though the Second Princess sent back all musicians.
雖然二郡主把樂人都送了回來
If not Chen Qianqian,
但是要是沒有陳芊芊
could the business of the Music and Dance Academy
我這教坊司
be so bad?
至於這樣的冷落蕭條嗎
She even allowed Lu Peng to play the lead role.
還讓陸鵬那種貨色當了頭牌
Lady. Don't be mad.
小姐 別生氣
Chen Qianqian is having a hard time too.
陳芊芊現在也不好過
She is scolded by thousands of people
龍骨之事
because of the case of Dragon Bone.
讓她遭萬人謾罵
She will get worse.
境況必然越來越糟
She deserves it.
活該
Zi Rui. Look.
梓銳 看
These trees were planted by me.
這是我親手打下的江山
Yes. Only a few trees are left.
對呀 就剩下這幾棵樹了
You don't understand.
你不懂
There is a saying goes,
有一句話叫
if I have Han Shuo, I will have everything in the world.
韓爍在手 天下我有
Though I have no money and power,
雖然我現在身無分文 無權無勢
I live at ease.
但是我活得逍遙自在
I don't have to struggle for a living.
一點生存壓力都沒有
I am very happy.
痛快
Young Master Han is from Xuanhu City and he has no power and influence here.
韓少君是玄虎城派來入贅的
He even can't protect himself.
自己都自身難保
How could he protect you?
怎麼可能還保護你呢
You don't know how capable he is.
你是不知道他有多厲害
Yes.
對
Don't be deceived by his appearance.
不能看表面
But you...
那你得
You are so weak.
你身子這麼弱
Why are you standing in the wind?
怎麼還在外面吹風
Han Shuo. Eat fruit.
少君 吃水果
Is it sweet?
甜不甜
Yes.
甜
Cooks in our family have all gone.
家裡的廚子都走了
I asked Bai Ji to buy some food from a restaurant.
我讓白芨去外面酒樓買了點吃食
Have a try
你嚐嚐
and see if you like it.
合不合你胃口
Why did you buy so much food?
你怎麼買了這麼多呀
It is too extravagant.
這多浪費啊
You know my situation.
你也知道現在咱家的情況
I don't know where my next meal is coming from.
有上頓沒下頓的
If...
要是
Please don't worry.
你放心
I have enough money
以我的資產
to support you.
養你還是綽綽有餘的
Your money?
你的資產
Are you talking about your dowry?
你說你的嫁妝吧
You should call them betrothal presents.
是聘禮
Something is wrong.
這不對吧
The small coffer you brought from Xuanhu City.
少君從玄虎城帶來的小金庫
If you say that they are dowry.
你要說是嫁妝
I have nothing to say.
我當然是沒什麼好說的
But if you say that they are betrothal presents,
但你要說這是聘禮的話
shouldn't you give them to me?
是不是得給我
You are right.
說得對
Young Master. Think it twice.
少君 三思啊
Do you want to manage my money?
你這是想管我的錢
No. No.
沒有 沒有
Why do you think that way?
我怎麼會這麼想呢
I just want to make it clear.
我只是想搞清楚
Are they betrothal presents or dowry?
這是聘禮呢 還是嫁妝
Bai Ji.
白芨
Bring the account book.
去把賬本拿來
Why are you trying to argue with Her Highness?
嘴上吃點虧就吃點虧吧
Let Her Highness call them dowry if she likes.
嫁妝就嫁妝吧
There is one thing.
只是有一點
Since I have given you my account book,
既然我把賬本交給你了
shouldn't you call me husband instead?
你是不是該改口叫我夫君了
What?
什麼
It doesn't matter.
沒關係
You are a lady of dignity.
三公主尊貴慣了
I will not force you.
不必勉強